地面控制，灶神一号离开追逐模式。
Ground control, Vesta 1 leaving chasing mode.
最后对接机动的导航图标计算方法。
Navicon calculating approach for final docking maneuver.
确认。继续接近。
Affirmative. Continue approach.
进入最后对接走廊。
Entering on final docking corridor.
Rubikon已经收到Navicon的数据。
Rubikon has received Navicon data.
准备好最后一个对接阶段。
Ready for last docking phase.
八十厘米的坚固隔热层，五厘米的强化玻璃。
Eighty centimeters of sturdy insulation, five centimeters of reinforced glass.
80厘米的坚固绝缘，5厘米……谁能想到太空旅行意味着除了盯着显示器什么都不做?
Eighty centimeters of sturdy insulation, five centimeters... Who would have thought space travel means doing nothing but staring at monitors?
八十厘米的坚固隔热层，五厘米的强化玻璃。
Eighty centimeters of sturdy insulation, five centimeters of reinforced glass.
放松。
Relax.
我放松。你凭什么认为我不放松?
I'm relaxed. What makes you think I'm not relaxed?
我放松。
I'm relaxed.
嗯…它是用来做这个的吗?
Uh... is it meant to do that?
它不是应该，承受我的体重吗?
Isn't it supposed to, you know, hold my body weight?
是的,你放松。
Yeah, you're relaxed.
我看得出来。
I can see that.
看，你必须按这里，然后它就会脱落。
See, you have to press here, and then it comes off.
是的，但我没按按钮。
Yeah, but I didn't press any button.
-它自己掉下来了我们会好起来的。
-It just came off on its own. -We'll be fine.
指挥官瓦格纳。
Commander Wagner.
这是卢比刚。
This is Rubikon.
你现在的职位是什么?
What is your current position?
导航图标显示射程350米，速率3.5。
Navicon indicates range 350 meters and rate 3.5.
350年?这里的读数是150米。
350? I'm reading 150 meters here.
他们的速度太快了。
They're way too fast for their position.
瓦格纳，我们给你150英镑。
Wagner, we got you at 150.
350或150，现在应该能看到空间站了，但我们还没看到。
350 or 150, the station should be in sight by now, but we have no visual contact.
在哪里?
Where is it?
-我就知道我就知道。-灶神1号，与Navicon的连接似乎有缺陷。
- I knew it. I fucking knew it. - Vesta 1, connection to Navicon seems flawed.
重新启动，这样我们就能再次控制局面。
Reboot so we get control again.
肯定的。
Affirmative.
嗯…汉娜。
Uh... Hannah.
他妈的什么?
What the fuck?
妈的，我们现在看到了。车站大约在90米外。
Shit, we see it now. The station is about 90 meters away.
-我要切换到手动模式。- - - - -不行 !禁止手动飞行!
- I'm switching to manual mode. - Negative! Flying manually is prohibited!
他们告诉我们永远不要碰的东西，太棒了。
The thing they told us never to touch, brilliant.
我得接手，否则我们可能会被帆撞到。
I need to take over or we might get hit by the sails.
瓦格纳，交给人工智能吧。
Wagner, leave it to the AI.
该公司不希望出现人为失误的风险。
The company wants no risk of human error.
汉娜!汉娜，汉娜，小心!
Hannah! Hannah, Hannah, watch out!
啊!
Ah!
——就在前面不远了。-是的,太近。
-That was close. -Yeah, too close.
初始化反向推进器。
Initializing reverse thrusters.
好吧。在自己的自由裁量权。
Okay. At own discretion.
好吧。
Okay.
好吧,嗯……
Okay, um...
减速捕捉接触点。
Speeding down for contact capture.
慢下来。
Slowing down.
-我们在监视器上看到你了。——率2.2。2.1.
- We got you on the monitors now. - Rate 2.2. 2.1.
瓦格纳，你的兑换率还是太高了。
Wagner, your rate is still too high.
是的。
Yes.
你最好告诉大家坚持住。
You better tell everyone to hold on.
哦,他妈的。
Oh, fuck.
率1.9。
Rate 1.9.
好了，我击中目标了。
Okay, I'm on target.
稳定。
Steady.
稳定了。
Steady now.
离开了!更多的离开!
Left! More left!
到达停车位置。
Arrived at parking position.
干得好,瓦格纳。
Well done, Wagner.
激活钩子以完成程序。
Activating hooks to finish procedure.
连接到空间站的重力场。
Connecting to station's gravitation field.
看到了吗?
See?
那他妈是什么?
What the fuck was that?
Navicon完全关闭了。
Navicon was completely off.
但这不是我们的错?
But it was not our fault?
尼布拉不能因此责怪我们，对吧?
Nibra cannot blame us for that, right?
电台的读数是正确的。
The station's readings were right.
好。
Good.
等一下。
Wait a second.
等
Wait.
她是一个士兵。
She's a soldier.
尼布拉为什么要派士兵来?
Why would Nibra send a soldier?
欢迎来到Rubikon。指挥官瓦格纳。艾博特医生，很高兴你加入。
Welcome to the Rubikon. Commander Wagner. Dr. Abbot, glad to have you on board.
刚才发生了什么，简森指挥官?你能解释一下吗?
What just happened, Commander Jenson? Can you explain?
错误一定发生在地面控制终端。
The error must have happened on ground control's end.
纳维康不知怎么地在没有通知的情况下失去了与你的航天飞机的连接。
Navicon somehow lost the connection to your shuttle without a notification.
你知道为什么吗?
Do you know why?
特蕾西会马上调查的。
Tracy will look into it immediately.
完事后把报告带来给我。
And bring me the report once you're done.
船员舱吗?
The crew cabins?
是的。嗯…请跟我来。
Yes. Um... Follow me, please.
我希望您对您的客舱满意。
I hope you'll be satisfied with your cabin.
虽然不多，但你的是我们最大的一个。
It's not much, but you've got the biggest one we've got.
哦,不,请…那真的没有必要。
Oh, no, please... that's really not necessary.
我希望你爸爸不会介意。
I hope your dad's okay about that.
为什么?他问过吗?
Why? Did he ask about or...
大姐姐!
Big sis!
哦我的上帝!
Oh my god!
嘿按钮!
Hey button!
这是从你房间看到的风景吗?
This is the view from your room?
看。
Look.
-这是我工作的地方。——给我。
- Look, this is my workplace. - Show me.
这是我的房间。
And this is my room.
太酷了!
So cool!
这是我的床。
And this is my bed.
所有我的。我不需要和任何人分享。
All mine. I don't need to share it with anyone.
你真是个糟糕的妹妹。把我一个人留在这里。
You're a shitty sister. Leaving me alone here.
看。
Look.
那是什么?
What's that?
某种跳蚤。
Some kind of fleas.
兵营里到处都是。
They're all over the barracks.
该死，汉娜，我得挂了。
Shit Hannah, I gotta go.
-指挥官真是个…——混蛋?
- The commander is such a... - Asshole?
是啊，彻头彻尾的白痴。
Yeah, a complete moron.
该死，这是紧急电话。
Damn, it's an emergency call.
希望不是公司的防御任务。
Hopefully not one of those company defense missions.
我讨厌这些。
I hate those.
克诺夫，听我说，好吗?
Knopf, listen to me ok?
无论如何，别再续约了，好吗?
No matter what, don't renew your contract, okay?
-只需要完成你当前的任务。-你疯了吗?
- Just complete your current one. - Are you nuts?
我们需要清空你所有的借方积分。
We need to clear off all of your Debit Points.
那我能在接下来的三年里不饿死就很幸运了。
Then I'll be lucky not to starve to death in the next three years.
照我说的做，好吗?
Just do as I say, ok?
等待。我被转移到中央尼布拉空气巨蛋，是你吗?
Wait. My transferal to the Central Nibra Air Dome, that was you?
你该走了。
You should get going.
汉娜，他们让你做什么作为交换?
Hannah, what are they making you do in exchange?
现在就去吧!
Go now!
那么,好吧。
Ok then.
爱你。
Love you.
你也一样。
You too.
致新团队，愿你和周五到达的其他三个人在一起有一个愉快的时间和富有成效的工作经验。
To the new crew, may you and the three others arriving on Friday have a good time... and a productive work experience together.
嗯…
Hmm...
所以我……我听说你是个化学家?
So I... I-- I hear you're a chemist?
是的，但我读了你所有的报告，还有…当然，这就是进行复杂的基因改造所需要的全部。
Yes, but I've read all of your reports and uh... Sure, that's all you need to conduct complex gene modification.
我相信你会做得很好。
I am sure you will do great.
只要你能服从命令。
As long as you can follow orders.
我的话没错。
My words exactly.
指挥官，我听说了你高超的航海技术。
Commander, I heard about your excellent navigational skills.
谢谢你！我也听说了很多你的事，医生。
Thank you. And I heard a lot about you too, Doctor.
希望都是好事。
Hopefully only good things.
是的。
Yeah.
指挥官，是激光通讯。
Commander, it's the laser comm.
拜托，好好享受派对，今天还是我的班。
Please, enjoy the party, it's still my shift.
我们再玩最后一场怎么样?
How about we play one last game?
让我们向新用户展示如何实现它。
Let's show the new ones how it's done.
来吧，新来的!
Come on, new ones!
确定。
Sure.
风险是什么?
What are the stakes?
Debit-points。
Debit-points.
好吧。
Okay.
达尼洛!-嗯?
-Danilo! -Uh-huh?
你能给瓦格纳指挥官一块蛋糕吗?
Can you give commander Wagner a piece of cake, please?
谢谢你！
Thank you.
抱歉，指挥官，我儿子……被取消有点私人恩怨。
Sorry, commander, my son takes this whole... being called off thing a bit personally.
你呢?
And what about you?
我只是想看看你玩什么类型的游戏。
I just want to see what type of game you play.
哇，我有七个。
Whoo, I got seven.
我要带一个…不，来两杯。
I'll take one... No, make it two.
你喜欢吗?
Up to your liking?
他们可能习惯了不同的空气圆顶标准，对吧?
They are probably used to different standards in the air-domes, right?
如果你想补充必需的氨基酸和矿物质，恐怕就只有这些了。对不起,domer-boy。
Well, if you want your essential amino acids and minerals covered, that's all you get, I'm afraid. Sorry, domer-boy.
嘿，你怎么了?
Hey, what's your problem?
什么都没有。
Nothing.
我只是想知道是什么让一个高管的儿子想来这样的地方。达尼洛!
I just wonder what makes an executive's son -want to come to a place like this. -Danilo!
你以为是我自己选择来这里的吗?
Do you think I chose to come here?
和这个老垃圾?
To this old piece of junk?
这么说，爸爸在惩罚你?
So then, daddy is punishing you?
为什么?
Why?
你作弊了吗?
Did you misbehave?
这是我的作品吗?
Is that my piece?
谢谢你！
Thank you.
指挥官瓦格纳。
Commander Wagner.
请给我一个字。
A word, please.
那是什么?
What is that?
这是我们明天的新航线。
It's our new flight route for tomorrow.
什么，他们为什么改了?
What, why did they change it?
在北半球有一个奇怪的雾团。
There is a strange fog cluster in the northern hemisphere.
-没人知道这是什么。-超过Östgrunden领土。
- Nobody knows what it is. - Over Östgrunden territory.
等一下,Ostgrunden ?
Wait, Östgrunden?
是的，而且还发生了死亡事故。
Yes, and there have been fatalities.
什么?发生了什么事?
What? What happened?
他们还不知道。
They can't tell yet.
Östgrunden不就是他们逮捕那些绿色斗士的地方吗?
Isn't Östgrunden where they arrested those green fighters activists?
他们是受害者吗，绿色斗士?
Were they the victims, the green fighters?
有几百个。
There were a few hundred.
但是他们说他们可以绕着你绕一圈，对吧?
But they said they can circumnavigate you around it, right?
要多花半天时间。
It'll take us half a day longer.
好吧。看起来不错。所以…按计划明天晚上。
Okay. Looks good. So... tomorrow evening as planned.
好吧。
Okay.
来吧，告诉我点什么。
Come on, give me something.
你知道，我们真的不应该在这里，对吧?
You know, we're not really supposed to be in here, right?
我在网上找不到任何东西，摄像头上也没有任何记录……所以我想试试这个。
I can't find anything on the Internet, there's nothing on the cameras... so I thought I'd try this.
所以…就这些吗?
So... that's it?
这个没用的大气分析系统?
This atmosphere analyzing thing that never worked?
我都没法让它动起来。
I can't even get it to budge.
你可以问我的，我和尼布拉有联系。
You could have asked me, I'm in contact with Nibra.
好吧，好像我相信一个政府公司说的话。
Right, as if I believe a single word a government company says.
拜托，他们不是敌人。
Come on, they're not the enemy.
嗯,是的,确实。是的,他们也是。
Uh, yes, actually. Yes, they are.
当然，如果你为他们工作就不会。
Of course, not if you work for them.
你担心你的朋友，是吗?
You worry for your friends, huh?
你很好。
You're good.
所有系统都已连接地面控制中心已发出最后指令。
All systems are online and ground control gave their final go.
你们准备好了吗?
You guys are ready?
是的,我们是。
Yes we are.
样本呢?
And the samples?
-爸爸,样本。-嗯?
-Dad, the samples. -Mmm?
哦，是的，当然。
Oh, yeah, of course.
这些母体文化会在延长的飞行时间中存活下来，对吧?
And these mother cultures will endure the extended flight time, right?
当然。当然,是的。
-Of course. -Of course, yes.
是的…这是我们的槽。我们走吧。
Yeah... That's our slot. Let's go.
指挥官瓦格纳。
Commander Wagner.
詹森!
Jensen!
再见我的朋友。
Goodbye my friend.
那么……谢谢你！
Well then... Thank you.
别让他们抓到你。
Don't let them catch you.
-请小心。——我知道。
- Please be careful. - I know.
好吧。
Alright.
-愿主与你同在。-我宁愿把他留在这儿陪你。
- May the Lord be with you. - I'd rather leave him up here with you.
这一点都不好笑，丹尼洛。一点都不好笑。
That's not funny, Danilo. Not funny at all.
-到达后联系我。——好的。
- Contact me once you've arrived. - Will do.
带着母体文化的儿子也快出生了，但我很确定他们也被操纵了。
The son is on the way now with the mother cultures, but I'm pretty sure they've been manipulated as well.
计划有变。
Well, there's been a change of plans.
委员会决定我们要尽早进入IKARUS。
The committee decided that we want to move on to IKARUS sooner.
已经决定了,什么时候?
Already, when?
显然是在接下来的几天。
Apparently in the next few days.
什么?但我还没能研究藻类的呼吸循环。
What? But I haven't been able to investigate on the algaes breathing cycle.
然后你必须更快地搜索才能准时到达。
Then you have to search faster to make it on time.
如果他发现了，他可能会销毁样本。
If he finds out, he might destroy samples.
准备好不被发现的小鹿。
Prepare IKARUS unnoticed then.
看，车站和藻类的交织比预期的要多。
Look, the station seems more interwoven with the algae than anticipated.
可能会更复杂…瓦格纳，准备好IKARUS。
It could be more complicated to just... Wagner, just prepare IKARUS.
希望你知道，他们中的一些人刚刚暴露在高水平的宇宙辐射中。
Hope you know that some of them were just exposed to high levels of cosmic radiation.
我得到了非常全面的指导。
I got instructed on them very thoroughly.
哦,好,好。
Oh, good, good.
所以你知道未经训练的人员在没有监督的情况下进入会发生什么吗?
So you are aware of what might happen when untrained personnel enters without supervision?
-别担心我。嗯。
-Don't worry about me. -Hmm.
听起来紧迫。
Sounds urgent.
他们已经着陆了吗?
Have they already landed?
不，他们还在运输途中。
No, they're still in transit.
rubkon呼叫灶神二号，你有什么要求?
Rubikon to Vesta 2, what's your request?
卢比刚!你能听到我们吗?
Rubikon! You can hear us?
我们都快瞎了!我们联系不上。
We-We're running blind here! We can't get contact.
无论是对地面控制还是对任何人。
Neither to ground control nor to anyone.
电台还在发送我们的信号吗?
Is the station still transmitting our signal?
简森,冷静下来。
Jenson, calm down.
我会和他们联系，然后马上给你答复。
I'll contact them and get back to you at once.
卢比肯呼叫地面控制?
Rubikon to ground control?
地面控制中心，收到吗?
Ground control, do you read?
Rubikon呼叫Nibra North。
Rubikon to Nibra North.
卢比刚呼叫Nibvision。
Rubikon to Nibvision.
这是怎么呢
What's going on?
我们还不知道。
We don't know yet.
他们在哪儿?
Where are they?
简森吗?-瓦格纳，是的，告诉我。
-Jenson? -Wagner, yes, tell me.
他们怎么说的?
What'd, what did they say?
我们也联系不上。
We can't make contact either.
你在开玩笑吧?这不可能是真的。
What are you kidding me? That can't be true.
我们试过所有的中转站，但没有人接电话。
We tried all staging posts but no one was answering.
简森，那Navicon呢?你收到了吗?
Jenson, what about Navicon? Are you receiving that?
就像你在灶神一号上一样。
It stopped just like yours in the Vesta 1.
等等，所以他们必须在没有任何地面人工智能的情况下降落?
Wait, so they would have to land without any ground AI?
他们受过这方面的训练吗?
Wh-- Are they trained for that?
我是说，我们没接受过这方面的训练。
I-- I mean, we weren't trained for that.
别——别担心，他们……他们的课程是预先设定好的。
Don't-- Don't worry, they... The... Their course is preprogrammed.
指挥官?
Right, Commander?
-是的。-是的。
-Yes. -Yes.
他们还要多久才能进入轨道?
How much time until they enter orbit?
还有54分钟。
Fifty four minutes from now.
好了，简森，我们这就去。
Okay, Jenson, we're on it.
我们会找到办法让你与地面连接。
We're gonna find a solution to get your connection to ground.
-别担心，好吗?-汉娜，快点。
- Don't worry, okay? - Hannah, hurry, please.
医生，给所有站发紧急信号。
Doctor, send an emergency signal to all stations.
即使是其他公司的电台，我也不在乎。
Even other company stations, I don't care.
加文，你跟我来。
Gavin, you come with me.
也许他们没有收到我们的信号。
Maybe they aren't receiving our signal.
我们得检查一下光学元件。
We have to check the optical unit.
- 0.75巴   -检查完毕
- Point seven five bar. - Check complete.
爸爸，你找到人了吗?
Dad, have you reached anyone yet?
没有。
Negative.
该死
Shit.
我们即将进入大气层。
We're about to enter atmosphere.
好消息是，你完全在轨道上。
Uh, good news are, you are exactly on course.
是的，但前提是在没有参数改变的情况下，对吧?
Yes, but only if no parameters change on the way, right?
等等，等等。
Hold on there, hold on there.
你会没事的。
You'll be fine.
你看到了吗，汉娜?
Do you see it, Hannah?
我对……五米之外。
I'm about... five meters away.
她做的怎么样?
How's she doing?
重要器官。
Vitals okay.
心跳有点加快，但这是正常的。
Heartbeat slightly increased, but that's normal.
我们收到测试信号了吗?
Do we get the test signal?
加文?
Gavin?
我们正在失去……
We're losing...
医生Kry——简森?五月天!五月天!五月天!
-Doctor Kry-- Jenson? -Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
——任何人!-简森，怎么了?
-To anyone! -Jenson, what's going on?
太空舱无法控制地升温!
The capsule is heating up uncontrollably!
我们要被烧毁了!
We're going to burn up!
加文，你听到了吗?
Gavin, can you hear that?
-蛋壳要破了!——达尼洛!
- The shell is about to break! - Danilo!
加文?
Gavin?
达尼洛!
Danilo!
灶神星2 !——达尼洛!
-Vesta 2! - Danilo!
达尼洛!达尼洛，怎么了?
Danilo! Danilo, what's going on?
加文?加文，下面怎么了?
Gavin? Gavin, what's going on down there?
简森吗?
Jenson?
快点，开门!
Come on, open up!
来吧!
Come on!
他妈的!
Fuck!
那不是我们的信号。
It wasn't our signal.
在那里，一切都……汉娜。船员。
Down there everything is... Hannah. The-- the crew.
我知道。
I know.
卢比肯呼叫地面控制中心。
Rubikon to ground control.
有人听到我们吗?
Does anybody hear us?
卢比刚到地面。
Rubikon to ground.
有人吗?
Anyone?
该死的,汉娜!你为什么不接电话?
Damn it, Hannah! Why aren't you answering?
我们正在去尼伯维恩的路上。
We're on our way to Nibvision right now.
他们正在撤出所有部队。他们所有人。
They are withdrawing all units. All of them.
我不知道发生了什么。
I don't know what's happening.
一片混乱。
It's chaos.
我们要去北边的掩体撤离。
We are moving to the northern bunkers to evacuate.
我到了那里会给你打电话，但我不能保证什么。
I will try to call you when I get there, but I can't promise anything.
当心我会试着去……
Take care. I'll try to get...
简森?
Jenson?
求救!
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
——任何人!-简森，怎么了?
- To anyone! -  -Jenson, what's going on?
太空舱无法控制地升温!
The capsule is heating up uncontrollably!
-我们要被烧毁了!-加文你听到了吗?
- We're gonna burn up! -  -Gavin, can you hear that?
——达尼洛!达尼洛!-蛋壳要破了!
- Danilo! Danilo! - The shell's about to break!
加文?
Gavin?
灶神星2 ?
Vesta 2?
达尼洛!达尼洛，怎么了?
Danilo! Danilo, what's going on?
对不起，我忘了开门。
Sorry, I forgot the door.
已经两天了，我还没联系上任何人。
It's been two days and I haven't been able to reach anyone.
无论从哪个方向，激光都无法穿透雾气。
The lasers can't get through the fog in either direction.
它会和Östgrunden一样吗?
Could it be the same as in Östgrunden?
那么快就传遍全球?
Spreading across the globe that quickly?
不，那需要几个月，不是几天。
No that would take months, not days.
我想我们会注意到陨石或火山。
Well, I think we would have noticed a meteorite or a volcano.
如果它之前就在那里呢?
And what if it was there before?
在大气中，只是还看不见?
In the atmosphere and just not visible yet?
你是说我们来这里时的Navicon问题吗?
You mean the Navicon problem when we came up here?
不。我也想过这个问题，但是——这就是为什么我一直在试图理解这个古老的大气分析仪。
Nah. I've thought about that too, but-- That's why I've been trying to understand this old atmosphere analyzer... thing.
怎么样了?
And how's that going?
啧啧……真的很好。
Tsk... Really good.
到目前为止，我只发现它可以在没有连接的情况下工作。
So far, I only found out that it works without a connection.
好。继续试。
Well. Keep trying.
Krylow博士吗?
Dr. Krylow?
我可以进来吗?
Can I come in?
我给你带了点吃的。
I brought you something to eat.
我知道你很伤心，但是…我们得谈谈藻类的事。
I know you're hurting but... We need to talk about the algae.
我们的氧气罐撑不了多久。
Our oxy tanks won't hold forever.
消失。
Go away.
天然气汇率有多发达?
How far developed is the gas exchange rate?
-呼吸共生是否有效?——去!
-Does the breathing symbiosis work or not? -Go away!
我们能在这上面待多久?
How long can we stay up here?
医生,请!
Doctor, please!
走开!
Go away!
加文?
Gavin?
加文，你能过来看看吗?
Gavin can you come and take a look at something?
加文!
Gavin!
哦,他妈的…他妈的,他妈的狗屎!
Oh, fuck... Shit, shit shit!
医生!
Doctor!
医生,帮我!
Doctor, help me!
这是一个紧急!医生,来了!
It's an emergency! Doctor, come!
快点!
Hurry up!
医生吗?来吧!
Doctor? Come on!
狗屎!多久?
Shit! How long?
他刚刚进入。
He just entered.
我在试着停止减压。
I'm trying to stop depressurization.
等一下。
Just a second.
嗯，在我们再次把它装满之前，它必须完全空出来。
Mhm, it has to empty completely before we can fill it up again.
不，那太长了。
No, that's, that's too long.
你在干什么?不!不!不!
What are you doing? No! No! No!
我想绕过锁定装置。
I'm trying to bypass the locking mechanism.
不，不，不!你会破坏它!
No, no, no, no! You'll destroy it!
你可以杀了我们。
Look, you can kill us.
我们所有人，相信我。
All of us, trust me.
就等着吧。请等一等。
Just wait it out. Please, wait it out.
来吧。
Come on.
白痴!
Idiot!
好的,空!现在最快的模式!
Okay, empty! Now fastest mode!
准备好了吗?
Ready?
-好的,打开了。-不，不，不!压力还是很大!
-Okay, it's open. -No, no, no, no! The pressure is still too much!
他妈的!快点，帮帮我。
Fuck it! Come on, help me.
加文!加文?
Gavin! Gavin?
嘿，你能听到我说话吗?
Hey, can you hear me?
嘴对嘴，来吧。
Mouth to mouth, come on.
好吧。
Okay.
十、九、八、七、六……
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six ...
五，四，三，二，一。
Five, four, three, two, one.
十、九、八、七、六……
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six ...
五，四，三，二，一。
Five, four, three, two, one.
好吧,再一次。
Okay, again.
好吧。
Okay.
小心。
Careful.
好吧，那不是撕裂。
Okay, that's not ripped.
……他没事吧?
Is he... Is he gonna be okay?
呃，我不知道。希望如此。
Uh, I don't know. Hope so.
他为什么要这么做?
Why the hell would he do that?
嗯?-他为什么要这么做?
-Hmm? -Why would he do that?
我不知道。
I don't know.
坦白地说，我不在乎。
Frankly, I don't care.
你怎么了?他刚想自杀，你却不在乎?
What's wrong with you? He just tried to kill himself and you don't care?
你说什么?
Excuse me?
你知道吗?你这样做。
You know what? You do it.
什么?
What?
间谍学院没教过你吗?
They didn't teach you that at spy academy?
哦，是的，我知道。
Oh, yeah, I know.
知道吗?
Know what?
你的藻类系统比你想承认的要先进得多?
That your algae system is much more advanced than you want to admit?
-那真是个大惊喜。-你以为我是白痴?
-Oh, that's a big surprise. -Oh, you think I'm an idiot?
我会告诉尼布拉的间谍任何事吗?不!
I'm gonna tell anything to a Nibra spy? No!
这不是间谍。
It's not spying.
他们资助了它，它属于他们。
They funded it, it belongs to them.
不,不!它不属于他们。
No, it doesn't! It doesn't belong to them.
它是我的。
It belongs to me.
它属于丹尼洛。
It belongs to Danilo.
你儿子的事我很遗憾。
I'm sorry about your son.
来吧，你一定累了。
Come on, you must be tired.
去睡觉吧，我能照顾他。
Just go to bed, I can take care of him.
加文?
Gavin?
我只闭了一秒钟眼睛。
I closed my eyes for one second.
嘿,加文?
Hey Gavin?
加文，你感觉如何?
Gavin, how-- how do you feel?
-让我检查一下你的耳朵…-放开我!
- Let me check your ear... - Get off me!
我…我很抱歉。我，我，冷静点。
I... I'm sorry. I-- I-- Calm down.
你不明白。
Y-You don't understand this.
-你需要躺下。-这雾有毒。
-You need to lay down. -This fog is toxic.
——好吗?- Th-These气溶胶…他们-冷静点。-他们都死了。
- Okay? - Th-These aerosols... They-- - Calm down. - They're all dead.
——好的。-他们都死了。
- Okay. - They're all dead.
没人能活下来!迪米特里……我…他们都死了。
Nobody can survive this! Dimitri... I... They're all dead.
看,看…呼吸,呼吸。深呼吸。
Look, look... Breathe, breathe. Deep breath.
我不能呼吸。
I can't breathe.
每个人都在那儿。
Everyone down there.
家庭吗?朋友吗?
Family? Friends?
有人在下面吗?
You have someone down there?
我的小妹妹。
My little sister.
对不起。
Sorry.
但这无关紧要。
But it doesn't matter.
反正我们在这里会窒息的。
We'll suffocate up here anyway.
我们这里是安全的。
We're safe here.
好吧?
Okay?
达尼洛和我…实现了与藻类的共生关系。
Danilo and I... achieved a working symbiosis with the algae.
我们可以生存。
We can survive.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
因为你告诉了一个尼布拉间谍。
For telling a Nibra spy.
不客气
You're welcome.
你要去哪里?
Where you going?
哇，你可真忙。
Wow, you've been busy.
即使空气有毒，也有掩体。
Even if the air is toxic, there are bunkers.
激光无法穿透迷雾，但是…也许这可以。
The lasers can't get through the fog, but... maybe this can.
我在试着让它工作。
I'm trying to get it to work.
这是吗?
Is this?
原来的国际空间站无线电系统，没错。
The old ISS radio system, exactly.
这是古老的技术。
That's ancient technology.
我是说，你真的认为还有人在用它吗?
I mean, do you really think anyone is still using it?
我会找到的。
I'll find out.
我只需要重新激活无线电天线。
I just need to reactivate the radio antenna.
无线电天线吗?
Radio antenna?
我，你一个人做不到。
I-- Well you can't do that alone.
是的,我知道。
Yeah, I know.
坐下。
Take a seat.
在扇区寻找一个电路…在部门B。
Look for a circuit in sector... in sector B.
你能看到吗?
Can you see it?
电缆缠结。
The cables are tangled.
好的,等待。
Okay, wait.
我知道了，确定。
I got it, affirmative.
好的，重新定向。
Okay, so redirect it.
你看到这些没用的东西了吗?
Have you seen all this useless crap here?
是的，我在空间站住了八年，我都见过了。
Ya, I've lived on the station for eight years, I've seen it all.
当处理旧零件的成本太高时就会发生这种情况。
That's what happens when it's too expensive to get rid of old parts.
你只要把它们堆在一起。
You just pile them up together.
你的主人朋友是对的。
Your domer-friend was right.
这个车站是个垃圾场。
This station is a junkyard.
是啊，跟我说说。
Yeah, tell me about it.
我年轻的时候，宇航员就像神一样。
When I was young, astronauts were like gods.
你年轻的时候，国家是有的，所以…好了，医生，已经接上了。
Well, when you were young, countries existed, so... Okay, Doctor, it's attached.
等待。
Wait.
很好。顺便说一句，你不用一直叫我医生。
Very good. By the way, you don't have to call me doctor all the time.
我的真名是迪米特里。
My real name is Dimitri.
我觉得这里有信号了。
I think I'm getting a signal here.
迪米特里。
Dimitri.
等我一下，让我扫描一下。
Give me a second, let me scan it.
明白了。
Got it.
好吧。
Okay.
让我们试一试。
Let's give it a try.
瓦格纳指挥官降落。
Commander Wagner to ground.
有人能听到我吗?
Can anybody hear me?
请,有人知道吗?
Please, anyone?
喂?
Hello?
他妈的!
Fuck!
加文不可能是对的。
Gavin can't be right.
她不可能死了。
She can't be dead.
打开这扇门!来吧!
Open the door! Come on!
你的耳朵痛吗?
Your ears hurt?
我，我可以给你开些止痛药，治耳朵的。
I-- I can give you some painkillers for the-- for the ears.
-我很好。我很好。你确定吗?
-I'm fine. I'm fine. -You're sure?
所以你说的话毫无疑问了吗?
So there's no doubt about what you said?
雾的气溶胶的化学结构是剧毒的。
The chemical structure of the fog's aerosols is highly toxic.
这是致命的。
It's lethal.
它们来自哪里?
Where do they come from?
我不知道，呃…对我来说，这似乎是某种……连锁反应?
I don't know, uh... To me it seems like some kind of... chain reaction?
从什么?
From what?
永冻层气体。
Permafrost gases.
我们已经警告人们很多年了而现在他们显然做出了反应。
We've been warning people about this for years And now they've obviously reacted with something.
也许是发电厂的毒素，其他污染，也许是另一场公司战争的化学武器。
Maybe Toxins from the power plants, some other pollution, maybe chemical weapons from another corporation war.
事实是，都在下面了。我们利用它。
Fact is it's, it's all over down there. We fucked it.
显然，经济比呼吸更重要。
Apparently, the economy was more important than breathing.
那空气圆顶呢?
And what about the air-domes?
它们代表一个特定的分子光谱。
They are for a very specific molecular spectrum.
只有一个装有氧气罐的封闭系统才能保护他们不受雾的影响。
Only a closed system with oxygen tanks could shield them from the fog.
但也有这样的掩体。
But there are bunkers like that.
疏散的掩体。我用它们训练。
Evacuation bunkers. I trained in them.
那里面的人会怎么样?嗯?
And what will happen to the people in there? Hm?
迟早，它们会耗尽食物，耗尽氧气。
Sooner or later, they'll run out of food, they'll run out of oxygen.
和我们一样。我们都只是行尸走肉。
Same as us. We're all just living corpses.
加文。-我不喜欢慢慢死去
-Gavin. -And I don't like the idea of a slow death.
我们想待多久就待多久。
We can stay here as long as we need to.
藻类气体交换起作用了。
The algae gas exchange works.
不。
No.
Wha?
没有?
No?
我不能这样生活。
Uh-uh, I can't live like this.
永远困在这个小金属罐里吗?
Stuck in this-- in this tiny metal can forever?
也许你们两个可以。
Maybe you two can.
-我就是做不到-是啊，那你有什么选择?
- I just can't. -  -Yeah and what is your alternative?
你想再试一次吗?
You wanna try it again?
看……这是你的生活，你的决定。
Look... it's your life, your decision.
我只是想让你知道，如果你再这么做，你也会杀了她。
I just want you to know that if you try it again, you will also kill her.
和我。
And me.
什么,为什么?
What, why?
我还没告诉你，这个系统是为六人设计的。
I didn't tell you this yet, but the system is designed for a full crew of six.
它们产生二氧化碳，系统将其转化为氧气。
They produce CO2 and the system converts it back into oxygen.
有效的气体交换最少需要三个人。
The bare minimum for an efficient gas exchange is three people.
加文，我们需要你的二氧化碳。
Gavin, we need your CO2.
我可以加入吗?
Can I join?
好吧。
Okay.
我生你的气，你知道吗?
I'm mad at you, you know?
谢谢你把我和这只臭脾气的老猫单独留在这里。
For leaving me alone here with this old grumpy cat.
什么?什么?
What? What?
什么?什么事这么好笑?
What? What's so funny?
只是，只是我，我拼命工作。
It's-- It's just that I-- I worked my ass off.
Debit-point Debit-point。
Debit-point for debit-point.
一次又一次的破任务，为了什么?
One shitty mission after another and for what?
对于这个吗?
For this?
我可以多参加些派对，像克诺普夫那样，或者…每隔一段时间休息一天。
I could have partied more, like Knopf, or... taken a day off every once in a while.
是的。
Yeah.
我觉得我真的把整个人生都搞砸了。
I think I really screwed up this whole life thing.
我也一样。
Same here.
你认为我没有把自己的生活搞砸，因为我一直在抗议，不洗，不剪t恤，还有…我很高兴我现在这么做了，不是吗?
You think I was not screwing up my life, by going on protests and not washing and cutting out T-shirts and... I'm really glad I did that now, aren't I?
是的。
Yeah.
没有行星B。
There is no planet B.
和迪米特里。
And Dimitri.
你觉得他是和他的同事在实验室开派对吗?
Do you think he was partying in his lab with his working symbiosis?
你能想象如果地球上的人知道我们是最后三个人类会怎样吗?
Can you imagine if they knew on Earth that we were the last three humans?
哦,我的上帝!
Oh, my God!
一群失败者和怪胎。
A bunch of losers and freaks.
我和我的朋友…为一个已经不复存在的星球而奋斗。
Me and my friends... fought so hard for a planet that doesn't exist anymore.
我花了这么长时间相信一件事，现在它不……任何意义。
I have spent so long believing in something, and now it doesn't... mean anything.
所以这位naïve活动家走了?
So the naïve activist is gone?
嗯…他……他本来就是个白痴。
Hmm... He... He was kind of an idiot anyway.
那太糟了。
That's too bad.
我喜欢他。
I liked him.
迪米特里吗?
Dimitri?
什么?
What?
是正常的吗?
Is that normal?
呃，他们从来不保持完全相同的绿色。
Eh, they never keep the exact same green color.
多久?
How much longer?
这次我真的要死了。
I'm dying this time for real.
两分钟!
Two more minutes!
是的，但是，但是棕色?这是——这是奇怪的。
Yeah, but-- but brown? That's-- that's weird.
如果…不，别担心，没事的。
It can happen if, uh... No, don't worry, it's fine.
哦,他妈的…哦，不，不，不，不，不。
Oh, fuck... Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
够了，我不干了。
That's it, I'm done.
他们得等到明天再看我的呼吸。
They'll have to wait for my breath until tomorrow.
加文，不是45分钟。
Gavin, it wasn't 45 minutes.
你知道那有多长吗?
Do-Do you even know how long that is?
不，你当然不知道，因为一直都是我和汉娜在叫卖。
No, of course you don't, 'cause it's always Hannah and me peddling.
事实上，我知道，因为每天早上你抱我的时候，我都在叫卖。
Actually, I do know because every morning when you cuddle, I peddle.
至少45分钟。
At least 45 minutes.
也许我们应该在闭路电视上看看。
Maybe we should check that on the CCTV.
也许我们应该。
Maybe we should.
好吧,好吧。你说呢?
Okay, okay. What do you say?
电影之夜吗?
Movie night?
-当然。什么其他的吗?
-Sure. -What else?
迪米特里吗?
Dimitri?
对，选个东西。我呃……我马上就来!
Uh, yeah, choose something. I'm uh... I'll come in a second!
抱歉,各位,抱歉。
Sorry, guys, sorry.
你在等我，真好。
Oh, you waited for me, that's nice.
你去哪儿了?
Where have you been?
我只是…我们在看什么?
I just, uh... What are we watching?
如果你不能重新激活网络，就什么都没有。
Nothing, if you can't reactivate the Internet.
显然，我们已经到达了内部电影库的尽头。
Apparently, we've reached the end of the internal movie library.
哦……
Oh...
我可以请你喝一杯。
I can offer you a drink.
更多。更多,更多!
More. More, more!
更多,更多,更多!
More, more, more!
Hannushka,就足够了。
Hannushka, it's enough.
你受够了，汉努什卡。
You had enough, Hannushka.
是的,谢谢你……爸爸。
Yeah, thank you... Daddy.
-好的……-在你所有的藻类功能中，这绝对是我最喜欢的。
-Okay... -Of all your algae's functions this is definitely my favorite.
是啊，这批有点太烈了。你可以看到。
Yeah, well, this batch is a bit too strong. You can see that.
如果我知道你的实验室里有一整个酿酒厂，我就…是啊，你会向妮布拉举报我的，对吧，小间谍?
If I'd known you had a whole distillery in your lab I would have just... Yeah, you would just report me to Nibra, wouldn't you, little spy?
是的,有可能。
Yes, probably.
等等,什么?
Wait, what?
等等，你不知道?
Wait, you didn't know?
汉努什卡是尼布拉派来偷我母亲培养的。
Hannushka was sent by Nibra to steal my mother cultures.
这他妈不是什么，不，不是偷。
What the fuck it's not-- No, not stealing.
——偷窃。只是拿走。-偷窃是一个很难听的词。
-Not stealing. Just taking away. -Steal is a harsh word.
把它拿走，然后去偷。
Take it away and steal.
-不。不。不。五周了，你现在才提这个?
-No. No. No. -Wh-- Five weeks and you're only mentioning this now?
我很抱歉，亲爱的。
I'm so sorry, my dear.
把它。
Take it.
三。
Three.
你，你把样本藏起来了?
You-- You were hiding the samples?
我是帮助。
I was helping.
几个月前，尼布拉改变了他们的合同。
A few months ago, Nibra changed their contract.
突然间，他们想让这个系统只在他们的空气穹顶上使用。
Suddenly they wanted the system to be exclusive for their air-domes.
和…我不介意。
And... I wouldn't mind.
我会收下那笔钱，那可是一大笔钱。
I would have taken the money, which was a lot of money.
贪婪的操。
Greedy fuck.
呃?是啊，而且并不为此感到羞耻。
Uh? Yeah, and not ashamed of it.
但是达尼洛,没有。
But Danilo, no.
他非常愤怒。
He was furious.
他决定让它成为公共领域。
He decided to make it a public domain.
他发现了什么秘密，我不知道，经销商。
He found some secret, I don't know, distributor.
听起来是个好人。
Huh, actually sounds like a good guy.
非常烦人，固执，粗鲁。
Extremely annoying, stubborn, rude.
有点像你。
A little bit like you.
厚脸皮的做好事的混蛋，是吧?
Cheeky little do-gooder shit, huh?
对不起。
Sorry.
谢谢你！你知道的。
Thank you... you know.
好了，好了，让我看看你们的本事。
Okay, okay, show me what you got, boys.
呃，是的，这是垃圾。
Ugh, yeah this is garbage.
-不!-现在你走了。
-No! -Now you are gone.
他妈的-砰。-不,加文!
What the f-- -Boom. -No, Gavin!
-哦…-滚开，我-不，我-汉努什卡，汉努什卡，住手-不!好吧,我……不。
- Ooh... - Fuck off, I-- No, I am-- -Hannushka, Hannushka, stop it. -No! Okay, I'm... no.
不!你们两个应该为清理穷人感到羞耻。
No! And you two should be so fucking ashamed cleaning out the poor.
我要跳舞，否则我就会死。
I need to dance or I'll die.
哦,不。
Oh, no.
加文!和女人跳舞。
Gavin! Dance with the woman.
来吧,跳舞。
Come on, dance.
-来吧，小情人。-请,不。
- Come on, lover boy. - Please, no.
-请…来吧……来吧。来吧!
-Please... -Come... Come on. Come on!
移动臀部，移动臀部。
Move the hips, move the hips.
不!我觉得你应该请迪米特里跳舞。
No! I think-- I think you should get Dimitri to dance.
——哦,明白了!-不，不!
- Oh, gotcha! - Oh, no, no!
-来吧!-不!不，我是科学家，我不是舞者，我不是-你是。-是的，医生会跳舞，来吧!
-Come on! -No! No, I'm a scientist, I'm not a dancer, I'm not-- -Yes you are. -Yes, doctors can dance, come on!
你绝对，绝对醉到可以跳舞了。
You're definitely, definitely drunk enough to dance.
来吧。停下。
-Come on. -Stop it.
来吧,迪米特里。是的。
Come on, Dimitri. Yes.
来吧。是的。
Come on. Yes.
如果还有其他人，请回答。
If anyone else is out there, please answer.
我们是躲在尼布拉总部地下掩体里的一群幸存者。
We are a group of survivors in a bunker underneath Nibra headquarters.
如果你能听到，请回复。
If you can hear us, please respond.
加文?
Gavin?
加文?嘿，你们醒醒!
Gavin? Hey, you guys wake up!
嘿,加文!加文,醒醒!
Hey Gavin! Gavin, wake up!
拜托，激光通讯又正常了，我，我和一个幸存者谈过了。
Come on, the laser comm worked again, I-- I talked to one of the survivors.
哦,来吧!来了!
Uh-- Come on! Come!
迪米特里。
Dimitri.
嘿,他们活着。下面还有幸存者呢。
Hey, they're alive. There's-- There are survivors down there.
是的,好,好……
Yeah, good, great...
卢比肯呼叫幸存者，能听到我们吗?
Rubikon to survivors, can you hear us?
喂?瓦格纳指挥官吗?这东西好用吗?
Hello? Commander Wagner? Is this thing working?
哦,上帝。
Oh, God.
-恩,是的。是的,它是。-我的天啊
-Um, yes. Yes, it is. - Oh, my God.
我们很高兴听到你的声音。
And we're happy to hear your voice.
嗯…这是埃丝特·陈-卡明斯基，我们的代表。
Uh... This is Esther Chen-Kaminski, I'm our representative.
你们有多少人?
How many of you are there?
我们这里差不多有300人。
We're almost 300 here.
发生袭击了吗?
Was there an attack?
老实说，我们不知道。
Honestly, we don't know.
雾来的太突然了，人们开始咳嗽、呕吐，真是……但士兵们把我们带进了地堡。
The fog came so suddenly and people started coughing and dropping, it was... But the soldiers brought us into the bunker.
但你是安全的，不是吗?
But you are safe, aren't you?
不，是氧。
No, it's the oxygen.
我们剩下的不多了。
We don't have much left.
但我猜克雷洛的藻类系统阻止了你，对吧?
But I guess Krylow's algae system is preventing that for you, right?
你是怎么知道藻类的?
How do you know about the algae?
我们中的一些人对这个有前途的项目持有股份。
Well, some of us own stock in this promising project.
你们是首席执行官还是什么?
So you're CEOs or something?
还有他们的家人，是的。
And their families, yes.
你们当中有兰德尔·艾博特吗?
Is there a Randall Abbot amongst you?
对不起,没有。
I'm sorry, no.
但是，这些藻类…体制为你提供了条件，对吧?
But, so these algae... The system provides for you, right?
克雷洛医生成功了吗?
I mean, Dr. Krylow made that work?
迪米特里吗?
Dimitri?
H-He的在这里。
H-He's in here.
汉娜是正确的。
Hannah was right.
有近300名幸存者。
There are survivors, almost 300.
真的吗?
Really?
是的，但更好。
Yeah, but even better.
在雾中有这些开口。
There are these openings in the fog.
非常小，但仍然是。
Very small ones, but still.
——嗯。-所以他们能听到我们
- Hmm. -  -That's why they could hear us.
他们已经转移了地堡的坐标。
They've already managed to transfer their bunker's coordinates.
下一步将是灶神星。
The next step would be the Vesta.
有了加文的大气分析，我可能会手动降落。
With Gavin's atmosphere analysis I might manage to fly down manually.
——做什么?-他们的地堡最多能提供三周的氧气。
-To do what? -Their bunker provides enough oxygen for three more weeks at best.
-嗯。如果……
-Mm-hmm. -If...
如果我们能把你的藻类带到那里，我们就能帮助他们。
If we could bring your algae down there, we could help them.
-好的。-听着，它们应该滋养一个封闭的系统。
-Okay. -Look, they're supposed to nourish a closed system.
不管下面是掩体还是上面是卢比肯。
It doesn't matter if it's a bunker down there or the Rubikon up here.
等一下。你是说我们不带导航图标就飞过去吗?
Hold on one second. So, you're suggesting we fly down without Navicon?
是的。
Yes.
我们可以拯救300条生命。
We could save three hundred lives.
我们认为这是一个值得冒的风险。
We think it's a risk worth taking.
假设我们，我们到达了地球。
Let's say we, we make it to Earth.
-我们怎么去地堡?-他们有机动氧气罐。
-How do we get to the bunkers? -They have mobile oxy-tanks.
他们可以来接我们，还有尼布拉实验室的设备。
They could pick us up, also the equipment from the Nibra Lab.
离我们降落的地方很近。
It's pretty close to where we'd land.
看来你都想通了。
Oh, it seems like you've figured it all out.
伟大的……如果我说不呢?
Great... So what if I say no?
什么?Wh-Why吗?
What? Wh-Why?
你知道，这有点不负责任。
You know, it's-- it's a little irresponsible.
而且非常非常愚蠢。
And very, very stupid.
不带导航图标就飞下来?你们疯了吗?
Flying down without Navicon? Are you out of your minds?
那我们怎么办，什么都不做吗?我们就看着他们死去?
So what, we do-- we do nothing? We just watch them die?
-你真的那么自私吗?你能不能别再说什么绿色战斗机了?
-Are you really that selfish? -Ca-Can you stop with this green fighter bullshit?
这不是你的意识项目。
It's not one of your awareness projects.
我们必须尽力帮忙。我们有道德责任。
We have to help if we can. We have a moral responsibility.
我唯一的道德责任就是让你们俩活着。
My only moral responsibility is to keep you and you alive.
——就是这样。-这不是达尼洛想要的吗?
-That's it. -Isn't this what Danilo would have wanted?
帮助人们吗?
To help people?
是的,他做到了。
Yes, he did.
现在他死了。
And now he's dead.
但我在这里说，“他们真倒霉。”
But I'm here and I say, "tough luck to them."
我现在知道了如何创造母亲文化。
I know now how to make mother cultures.
所以我们不需要你的帮助。
So, we don't need your help.
你不能碰它们。
You're not gonna touch them.
-你明白我的意思吗?
-Hey -You understand what I'm saying?
你不许碰它!
You're not gonna touch it!
停!说真的,你们。
Stop! Seriously, you guys.
坐下，你们两个。
Sit down, both of you.
我们必须做出决定。
We have to make a decision.
这真的说不通。
It really doesn't make sense.
来吧，我们很好。
Come on, we are fine.
我们在这里很好。
We are good here.
我们，我们想待多久就待多久。
We, we can stay here as long as we want.
真的吗?这是你的计划吗?
Really? That's your plan?
这么长时间你在实验室里完全疯了吗?
Have you gone completely crazy in that lab all this time?
你没资格跟我说什么疯狂，先生。
You don't get to talk to me about crazy, mister.
想自杀的不是我。
I am not the one who tried to kill himself.
你到底有多想再来一次?
How desperately are you trying to do it again?
真的吗?你要去那里?
Really? You're gonna go there?
我还没跟你说完呢。
Hey, I'm not done talking to you.
嘿,嘿!回来!来,达尼洛!
Hey, Hey! Come back! Come-- Danilo!
你没事吧?
You okay?
没什么,这是……
Nothing, it's...
嘿,嘿,嘿。你没事吧?
Hey, hey, hey. You okay?
没什么，只是，我猜是你的杜松子酒。
It's nothing, it's just-- It's just your schnapps, I guess.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
只是预防措施，只是想确保一切正常。
Just a precaution, just want to make sure everything is fine.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你知道，他是对的。
He's right, you know.
如果他们是地球上最后的人类怎么办?
What if those are the last people on the planet?
好。
Well.
如果他们是地球上最后的人类，也许从头开始并不是一个坏主意。
If these are the last people on the planet Earth, maybe it's not that bad of an idea, to start it all from scratch.
迪米特里,来吧。
Dimitri, come on.
好吧。告诉我，这些人，这些可爱的ceo，为你做过什么?
Okay. Tell me, what have these people, these lovely CEOs, ever done for you?
他们把我从泥土里救了出来。
They got me out of the dirt.
嗯。
Hm.
让你成为一名士兵，在他们的军队里为他们服务。
Yeah and made you a soldier to serve them in their army.
你做了什么?
You done?
睡不着吗?
Can't sleep?
是她吗，克诺夫?
Is that her, Knopf?
她的真名是米娅。
Her real name is Mia.
这是我从她那里得到的最后一条信息。
This is the last message I got from her.
我想知道她当时在哪里。
I'm trying to find out where she was.
好吧?
Okay?
诺普夫驻扎在距离尼布拉中心掩体五小时路程的地方。
Knopf was stationed five hours away from the Nibra central bunker.
那个地区还有其他地堡，而且……她也收到了疏散令。
There are other bunkers in that area and... she got an evacuation order too.
也就是说她可能还活着?
That means she could still be alive?
汉娜，你为什么不告诉我?
Hannah, why didn't you tell me?
因为这很愚蠢。
'Cause it's-- it's stupid.
机会这么小。
It's such a small chance.
我们正准备出发。
We're preparing for departure.
你能帮我们装母质吗?
Will you help us load the mother cultures?
迪米特里，你要么跟我们走，要么…或者你留下。
Dimitri, either you come with us or... Or you stay.
什么?这里也有吗?呃，不，不，不要说我们现在失去他们了。
What? In here as well? Eh-- No, no, don't say we're losing them now.
这是让我们留下来的诡计吗?
Is this a trick, to make us stay?
不，这不是恶作剧。
No, it's not a trick.
它真的发生了。
It's really happening.
在整个车站。
In the whole station.
他们生病了吗?
Are they sick?
我也是这么想的。
That's what I thought.
那又怎样?我们不能把他们打倒还是?
So what? We can't bring them down or?
迪米特里。
Dimitri.
——是你。-我让他们走…没有你的监督我是不会碰它们的。
-It's you. -I make them go... I don't even touch them without your supervision.
你不需要碰它们。
You don't need to touch them.
它们在空间站的营养循环中以我们的尿液为食。
They feed from our urine in the station's nutrient cycle.
所以它们变色是因为汉娜的尿吗?
So they've changed color because of Hannah's pee?
完全正确。
Exactly.
是啊，是啊，你差点就骗到我了。
Yeah, yeah, you almost got me.
来吧。
Come on.
藻类对激素极其敏感。
The algae is extremely sensitive to hormones.
这是你体内高水平的HCG造成的。
It's your high levels of HCG that do it.
不，士兵不能怀孕。
No, soldiers can't get pregnant.
我们连月经都没有。
We don't even get our periods.
在我的职责结束前，我是不育的。
I'm-- I'm sterile till the end of my duty.
除非你的激素诱导剂和控制装置失去联系足够长时间。
Unless your hormone inducer loses connection with its control unit for a long enough time.
但是藻类没有问题，对吧?
But the algae is fine, right?
我们不会失去它?
We won't lose it?
藻类很好。
The algae is fine.
另一方面呢?
That, on the other hand?
如果我们飞下来…
If we fly down...
这些人需要我们的帮助。
These people need our help.
来吧。
Come on.
等,汉娜,等。
Wait, Hannah, wait.
停止。
Stop.
搞什么，伙计?
What the fuck, dude?
他说得对，他说得对。
He's right, he's right.
请。
Please.
开始加载母体培养。
Start loading the mother cultures.
明天我们要离开。
We're leaving tomorrow.
我来准备灶神星。
I'll prepare the Vesta.
汉娜。
Hannah.
汉娜!
Hannah!
大便。来吧。
Shit. Come on.
一遍吗?
Again?
你可能没注意到，我刚杀了我们俩。
In case you didn't notice, I-- I just killed us.
所以,是的,一次。
So, yeah, again.
是啊，但其他八次你都成功了。
Yeah, but the other eight times you made it.
你只是累了，就这样。
You're just getting tired, that's all.
你给我的飞行通道太狭窄了。
This flight corridor you gave me is fucking narrow.
那他们该庆幸坐在座位上的是你。
Well, then they're lucky that it's you sitting in the seat.
汉娜，我真的觉得我们应该谈谈…关于这一切。
Hannah, I really think we should talk about the... about all this.
这意味着什么呢?
What does this mean now?
没有，这意味着什么。
Nothing, this means nothing.
汉娜……
Hannah...
是不是很可能别说了，好吗?我…不!他妈的。
isn't it likely that-- Stop it, okay? I... No! Fuck.
我会在重返大气层或者着陆的时候或者没有空间站的辐射罩的时候失去它。
I'm going to lose it at re-entry or landing or without the station's radiation shield.
好吧，这真是太操蛋了。
Okay, that's-- that's super fucked up, yeah.
抱歉，我，我不是故意的
Sorry, I-- I didn't mean to--
反正也没机会了，我是说，就算我们留下来。
It has no chance anyway, I mean, even if we stayed.
我不能在这里养孩子。
I can't raise a baby here.
只有你，我和迪米特里?
Just you, me and Dimitri?
这改变不了什么。
This changes nothing.
这只会让事情变得更糟。
It just makes the whole situation shittier.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
我真的害怕。
I really am.
听着，这个可能没机会了。
Look, this one probably doesn't have a chance.
但是，当我们在那里的时候…你是说你想和我生个孩子吗?
But, when we're down there... Are you saying you want a baby with me?
为什么不呢?
Why not?
我的意思是,想象。
I mean, imagine.
会踢屁股。
It'd kick butt.
我的大脑，你的肌肉。
My brains, your muscles.
是的。
Yeah.
是啊，你说得对，我真的太累了。
Yeah, you're right, I'm-- I'm definitely too tired for this.
十次中有八次着陆就够了，对吧?
Eight landings out of ten must be enough, right?
好吧，给我最后一个。
Okay, bring me the last one.
这真的够300人吃吗?
And this is really enough for 300 people?
是的，这是最低金额。
Yep, that's the minimum amount.
什么?
What?
你又觉得我在骗你吗?
Again, you think I'm tricking you or something?
只是，你一整天都没说过一句反抗的话。
It's just, you've not said one word of resistance the whole day.
什么……你想从我这里得到什么?
What... What do you want from me?
你以为我会蠢到带着没用的海藻菌飞下来吗?
You think I'm stupid enough to fly down with algae cultures that don't work?
我是说，没有你们俩我待不下去了。
I mean, I can't stay here without you two.
所以,你赢了。祝贺你。
So, you won. Congratulations.
你还想从我这里得到什么?
What else do you want from me?
好了，检查完毕。
Okay, all checks are done.
你准备好了吗?
Are you ready for this?
不。
Nope.
完美的。
Perfect.
灶神一号，收到飞行走廊。
Vesta 1, flight corridor received.
尼布拉中心，92分钟后再联系你。
Central Nibra, contacting you again in 92 minutes.
好吧，我们祝你一路平安，我们正在看联系窗口刚刚过去。
Okay, we'll wish you a safe journey and we're looking-- And the contact window's just passed.
好了，关上内门。
Okay, closing the inner door.
嗯…那是什么?
Uh... What is that?
飞机没有反应。
The jets are not responding.
哇……
Whoa...
那是什么?
What is that?
喷气坦克过热了，但是…我们甚至还没有点燃。
The jet tanks overheated but... We haven't even ignited.
过热?-温度一直在上升，但是…妈的，这不可能。
-Overheated? -The temperature keeps rising, but... fuck, that can't be right.
汉娜,什么?
Hannah, what?
我们有超压。
We have overpressure.
-哦,大便。吹嘘的毫无意义。
-Oh, shit. -Makes no sense.
我需要释放氧气罐。
I need to release the tanks.
-工作吗?-阀门打不开。
-Did it work? -The valves are not opening.
-试试煤气出口!我试过!
-Try the gas outlet! -I tried!
它们一定是热得变形了!
They must have deformed under the heat!
水箱有多热?
How hot are the tanks?
汉娜?
Hannah?
汉娜!
Hannah!
立即解开!现在出去!
Unfasten immediately! Get out now!
——加油!-来吧，来吧来吧。
- Come on! - Come on, come on. Come on.
快点，我们要爆炸了!
Come on, we're gonna explode!
把自己放在一起。
Put yourself together.
你振作起来了!来吧!
You put yourself together! Come on!
走吧!
Go!
-他妈的?-什么?
-What the fuck? -What?
看。灶神星的冷却系统在近11小时前关闭了。
Look. The Vesta's cooling system shut down almost 11 hours ago.
这就是水箱过热的原因。我会改变太阳能板的方向。
That's why the tanks overheated. I'll redirect the solar panels.
光靠影子已经不行了。看看温度。
Shadow alone won't do it anymore. Look at the temperature.
我们需要解耦它。
We need to decouple it.
不。不，肯定还有别的办法。
No. No, there has to be another way.
我们可以手动倒掉水箱，对吧?
We can dump the tanks manually, eh?
可以工作。
That could work.
只能从灶神星内部，但那太危险了。
Only from inside the Vesta, but that's far too dangerous.
加文,停止!
Gavin, stop!
它随时都可能爆炸!
It could blow up any second!
他妈的!
Fuck!
他必须通过整个冷却装置。这是不可能的。
He has to go through the whole cooling block. That's impossible.
他是自杀。
He's killing himself.
我们所有的人。
All of us.
还能解耦吗?
Can you still decouple?
-不不不!不!——等等!汉娜!
- No, no, no! No! - Wait! Hannah!
不!不!
No! No!
停!
Stop!
不!
No!
汉娜,谢谢!
Hannah, please!
不!
No!
我不得不。
I had to.
你做得对，指挥官。
You did the right thing, commander.
他会死的。
He would have died.
我知道，在这里似乎不算什么…但是,呃…
I know, doesn't seem like much up here... But, uh...
这个地方救了我们的命。
this place saved our lives.
可以回家。
Could be home.
你觉得怎么样?
How was it for you?
有一个孩子?
Having a child?
大声。
Loud.
伤脑筋。
Nerve-wracking.
让人筋疲力尽。
Exhausting.
很神奇的。
Amazing.
你无法想象你会像爱这个小东西一样爱别人。
You can't possibly imagine loving anyone like you love this little creature.
好吧。
Okay.
我们不需要两个人来告诉他们。
We don't need two people to tell them.
但我是……-走或者我走。
-But I was... -Go or I go.
你这么做是因为怀孕吗?
Did you do it because of the pregnancy?
不。我这么做是因为我们。
No. I did it because of us.
灶神星1 ?
Vesta 1?
灶神一号，我们探测不到你的信号。
Vesta 1, we can't detect your signal.
你读过吗?
Do you read?
灶神星1 ?
Vesta 1?
是的，埃斯特，我们到了。
Yes, Esther we're here.
加文，你在哪里?发生了什么事?
Gavin, where are you? What happened?
IKARUS是什么?
What's IKARUS?
他们说你会知道的。
They said that you would know.
我的实际任务。
My actual mission.
一旦我找到了一个工作母菌，我就会把整个藻类实验室都搞垮。
Once I found a working mother culture, I was to bring down the entire algae lab.
它可以单独弹射和降落。
It can be ejected and flown down separately.
-什么?-这是一次秘密军事行动。
-What? -It was a secret military operation.
我很惊讶这些ceo竟然知道这事。
I'm surprised these CEOs even know about it.
W-Wait。
W-Wait.
我们能继续下去吗?
C-Can we go down with it?
它不是为乘客设计的，也不能被驾驶。
It's not made for passengers and can't be steered.
没有导航图标，我们只能在一个合理的时刻分离它，然后…往好处想吧。
Without Navicon we can only detach it at a calculated moment and... hope for the best.
但从理论上讲，如果我们为乘客改装的话，我们可以登上飞机。
But theoretically, we could board it if we adapted it for passengers.
汉娜，搞什么鬼?你为什么不告诉我还有一次重返地球的机会?
Hannah, what the fuck? Why didn't you tell me that there was another chance for re-entry?
因为这不是一个严肃的选择。好吧?
Because it's not a serious option. Okay?
三个人对300人。
Three people against 300.
是的，如果其他碉堡成功了，可能会更多。
Yes, or even more if other bunkers made it.
我觉得我们应该这么做。
I think we should do it.
如果我们不尝试，那他们就完了。
If we don't try, then it's done for them down there.
我们不能让这种事发生。
We can't let that happen.
这不是我们的事，对吧?
This is bigger than us, right?
对吧?
Right?
你，混蛋，把灶神星和冷却系统断开了。
You, asshole, disconnected the Vesta from the cooling cycle.
我们差点因为你而死。
We almost died because of you.
我不想，我只是，我只是想推迟。
I didn't want, I just-- I just wanted a delay.
这是个意外。
It was an accident.
是啊，我不知道瓣膜可以关闭。
Yeah, I didn't know the valves can close up.
我不能让发生在丹尼洛身上的事发生在我们身上。
I couldn't let what happened to Danilo happen to us.
废话。
Bullshit.
你这么做只是因为你是个自私的懦夫。
You just did it because you're a selfish coward.
你知道这是什么吗?
You know what this is?
是的。
Yeah.
你知道它的作用吗?
And you know what it does?
我在某个时候发现的，是的。
I found out at some point, yes.
很好。因为这就是我们现在要做的
Good. 'Cause that's what we'll do now.
我们会把共生文化带回这里，然后飞下去。
We will pump back the symbiosis cultures in here and we will fly down.
这么说你一直都知道伊karus的存在?
So you knew about IKARUS all of this time?
你什么都没说?
And you didn't say anything?
你也不想这样。
You didn't want this either.
是吗?
Did you?
加文是正确的。
Gavin is right.
我们需要帮助。
We need to help.
关心自己的生活没什么可耻的，汉娜。
There is no shame in caring for your own life, Hannah.
特别是现在。
Especially now.
阻止它。
Stop it.
你有没有问过自己为什么尼布拉突然这么需要海藻?
Have you ever asked yourself why Nibra needed the algae so bad all of a sudden?
我是说，这么多年来他们根本不在乎。
I mean, for years they didn't give a fuck.
现在他们突然什么都想要了。
Suddenly they want everything, now.
他们现在就需要这个系统。
They need the system now.
他们把你送到太空去拿，为什么?
They send you to space to get it, why?
为什么,现在?
Why, now?
你想说什么?
What are you trying to say?
他们知道。
They knew.
他们知道一场灾难即将来临。
They knew a catastrophe was coming.
他们只是没有告诉任何人。
They just didn't tell anyone.
他们为什么要这么做?
And why would they?
他们不想和别人共用地堡。
They didn't want to share their bunkers.
你真的认为，如果是反过来，他们会给你藻类吗?
Do you really think, they would give you their algae, if it was the other way around?
我们已经做出了决定。
We've made a decision.
按照你的要求，我们把藻类实验室派给你了。
We're sending the algae lab down to you, like you asked.
但我们会和它一起来。
But we're coming with it.
好的，我们很期待。
Okay, we're looking forward to that.
等等，开始前还有一件事。
Wait, one more thing before we start.
我要和其中一个士兵谈谈。
I need to talk to one of the soldiers.
但我是我们的代表。
But I am our representative.
是的，但伊卡拉斯是军事任务，所以。
Yes, but IKARUS is a military mission, so.
呃……好吧。
Eh... okay.
事情是这样的……这里没有士兵。
The thing is... there are no soldiers here.
但你说士兵们带你进了掩体。
But you said the soldiers brought you into the bunkers.
是的，他们把我们带到这里，但是…我们空间有限。
Yes, they brought us here, but... we have limited space.
我们可以容纳300名平民。
We have room for 300 civilians.
家庭。
Families.
那又怎样?你……你就把它们丢在外面了?
So what? You... You just left them outside?
去死吗?
To die?
他们履行了自己的职责。
They did their duty.
这是尼布拉的命令?
That was Nibra's order?
给所有撤离的士兵?
For all evacuation soldiers?
汉娜，你的工作就是让我们活着!
Hannah, it is your job to keep us alive!
你说谎了。
You lied.
不，我们没有撒谎。
No, we didn't lie.
你只是假设了你想相信的。
You just assumed what you wanted to believe.
抱歉，但你在想什么?
I'm sorry, but what were you thinking?
我们只想活下去，仅此而已。
All we want is to live, nothing more.
我们希望我们的孩子能活下去。
We want our kids to survive.
你不能因此责怪我们。
I mean, you can't blame us for that.
他妈的!啊!
Fuck! Ugh!
来吧，从地板上起来。
Come on, get off the floor.
不,我完成了。
No, I'm done.
汉娜，他们几天内就会缺氧。
Hannah, they'll run out of oxygen within days.
是啊，为什么我这样的炮灰会在乎?
Yeah, and why would cannon fodder like me care?
他们根本不在乎我。克诺夫出版社。
They didn't give a shit about me. Or Knopf.
或者我的父母。
Or my parents.
显然，金钱和特权也不能让你在地堡里有一席之地。
Apparently, money and privilege don't get you a spot in the bunker either.
你知道下面也有孩子，对吧?
You know that there are children down there too, right?
那么这个呢?
And what about this one?
你说过我们不能在这里养。
You said that we couldn't raise it here.
为什么不是呢?我的意思是……这地方比我以前住过的任何地方都好。
Why actually not? I mean... this place is better than anywhere I lived before.
变老吗?
Growing old here?
从来没有看到地球?
Never seeing Earth?
那是什么样的生活?
What kind of a life is that?
至少是一生。
At least a life.
我…我不明白。
I... I don't get it.
你只是受伤了还是真的想要这个孩子?
Are you just hurt or do you really want this baby?
我不知道，好吗?
See, I don't know, okay?
我从没想过要孩子。
I never thought about having a child.
成家就意味着回到贫穷的生活。
Having a family meant going back to being poor.
不服从就意味着贫穷。
Not obeying meant being poor.
一个士兵甚至没有这个选择。
A soldier doesn't even have that choice.
这个选择比拯救我们的世界更重要。
And that choice is more important than saving the rest of our world.
是的。
Yes.
你不会明白的，domer。
You wouldn't understand that, domer.
对你这样的人来说，玩《拯救世界》很简单
For someone like you, it's easy playing "Save the World."
但不是每个人都有一个把他送到这里来避难的爸爸如果其他事情都泡汤了。
But not everyone has a daddy who sends him up here for safety if everything else goes down the drain.
你真的这么想吗?
Is that really what you think?
嗯。
Huh.
加文?
Gavin?
开门。
Open the door.
我要完成我们开始的事情。
I'm finishing what we started.
你要把我丢下吗?
Are you leaving me behind?
不，但我得把它做完。
No, but I just need to finish up.
只是等待。
Just wait.
你怎么知道我不会阻止你?
How can you know I won't stop you?
因为你是个好人。
Because you're a good person.
你知道这是对的。
And you know that this is right.
汉娜,等等!停!
Hannah, wait! Stop!
加文,阻止它!
Gavin, stop it!
请动!
Please, move!
不!加文!加文!加文!
No! Gavin! Gavin! Gavin!
不,住手!
Don't-- Stop it!
我不能让你这么做。
I can't let you do this.
汉娜，我们能谈谈吗?我——我不能。我只是不想。
Hannah, can-- can we talk about this? I-- I can't. I just don't want to.
汉娜,请…
Hannah, please just...
他妈的!
Fuck!
汉娜，你能搞定的，对吧?
Hannah, You can fix this, right?
汉娜?
Hannah?
我很抱歉……我想留下来。
I'm sorry... I wanna stay.
加文?
Gavin?
来吧。
Come on.
让我们看看是否能以某种方式修复IKARUS。
Let's see if we can fix IKARUS somehow.
是的,什么?
Yeah, what?
为什么?
Why?
我们需要三个人呼吸否则气体混合物就会坍缩。
We need three breathers or the gas mix collapses.
你的言语。
Your words.
你……你认为是加文干的…是的。
You... You think Gavin did it... Yeah.
他把自己的意志强加给我们。
He forced his will on us.
他得到了他想要的。
He got what he wanted.
-什么?-不…不,不,不……
-What? -No... No, no, no...
我们需要三个呼吸器，对吧?
We need three breathers, right?
迪米特里?
Dimitri?
我是在他试图…我只是，我只是不想让他伤害自己。
I said it after he tried to... I just-- I just didn't want him to harm himself.
我想救他。
I wanted to save him.
你这个白痴，你做了什么?
You idiot, what have you done?
停
Stop.
我很抱歉。我没有……-好了，别说了。
-I'm sorry. I didn't... -Okay, just stop.
不,不,不!
No, no, no!
不，不，不，现在。
Nein, nein, no, now.
-我明白了。我做的事。-不不不!
- I got you. I do. - No, no, no!
我们走吧。Pashli !
Let's go. Pashli!
我们走吧!
Let's go!
一，二，三!
Eins, zwei, drei!
你!
You!
晚安,嗯?
Good night, yes?
好吧!Warte Warte。
Okay! Warte, warte.
你好,你好吗?有任何人吗?喂?喂?
Hello, hello? Is there anyone? Hello? Hello?
喂?
Hello?
伙计们，这东西起作用了。
Look, guys, the thing is working.
给我!喂?
Give it to me! Hello?
你在里面吗?在盒子里吗?
Are you in there? In the box?
不，我们在南部营地。
No, we are in the southern camps.
——你呢?你叫什么名字?克诺夫
-And you? What's your name? -Knopf.
-克诺夫 …-你在哪里?
- Knopf... - Where are you?
呃……卢比刚。
Eh... Rubikon.
你还能在外面玩吗?
Can you play outside there again too?
不行，妈妈说我们在外面不能呼吸。
No, Mom says we can't breathe outside.
所以他一定还在北方的某个地方。
So he must still be somewhere up North.
嘿,嘘。那就问问她你能不能过来
Hey, shh.  Well, then ask her if you can come down here.
大人们总是在寻找幸存者。
The grown-ups are always searching for survivors anyway.
他们说我们必须互相帮助，因为现在一切都不一样了。
They say we must help each other cause everything is different now.
停!说真的，你不能来吗?
Stop it! Seriously, can't you come?